<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Scout</name>
    <description>Scout Background</description>
    <author url="https://github.com/Pushingthrough12/Aurora-Aereni-Elf">u/Pushingthrough12</author>
    <update version="0.0.1">
      <file name="scout-background.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Pushingthrough12/Aurora-Homebrew/master/scout-background.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>

  <element name="Scout" type="Background" source="Silverware DnD" id="ID_SLV_BACKGROUND_SCOUT">
    <description>
      <p>You are up to the missions of the scout initiative. </p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li>
          <strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two Skills.
        </li>
       
        <li>
          <strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two Tools
        </li>
        <li>
          <strong>Equipment:</strong> Monocular, Compass, Local Area Map, Traveler's Clothes, Explorer's Pack, Pouch containing 10g
        </li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SLV_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCOUT_NETWORK" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
      <p>Scouts are generally good at reconnaissance. Their skill at finding and tracking down targets, as well as their relationship to their charges, affect how they act and think.</p>
    </description>
    <rules>
     
      <select type="Proficiency" number="2" supports="Skill" />
      <select type="Proficiency" supports="Tool" number="2" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SLV_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCOUT_INITIATIVE_SPELLS" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SLV_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCOUT_NETWORK" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select name="Personality Trait" type="List" optional="true" number="2">
        <item id="1">I am always quiet and stoic, rarely speaking or acting when I work.</item>
        <item id="2">I am aggressive and often get in people’s faces while I work, trying to make sure others know to keep a distance.</item>
        <item id="3">I often hide in crowds while keeping an eye on my charge; stepping in out of the shadows when needed.</item>
        <item id="4">I always check the shadows wherever I go; you can never be too safe.</item>
        <item id="5">I fuss over my charge, swiftly and deftly tending to their every need; acting more like a servant than a bodyguard.</item>
        <item id="6">I don’t like when strangers get too close to me or my friends; keep your distance, and we’ll be fine.</item>
        <item id="7">I’m used to sleeping on the road and in uncomfortable situations; but I wake up at the slightest noise.</item>
        <item id="8">I always make sure that when we have to sleep, at least one person is on lookout.</item>
      </select>
      <select name="Ideal" type="List" optional="true">
        <item id="1">Protection. it is my job to protect others; I would die for the ones I guard. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Guardian. I want to protect everyone, as best I can. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Fluid. When attacked, you can’t be rigid and unmoving; you need to adapt to the situation. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Money. I honestly just want to get paid; I couldn’t care less about my charges. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="5">Betrayal. As a bandit, you have to wait for people to wander out into the wilderness to kill them. As a bodyguard, they’ll wander out into the wilderness with you! (Evil)</item>
        <item id="6">Friendship. I just don’t want my friends to die. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select name="Bond" type="List" optional="true">
        <item id="1">I am still loyal to my original master; and would die for them.</item>
        <item id="2">I will get revenge on the one who slaughtered those I was meant to defend.</item>
        <item id="3">I owe my life to my old master; and they owe their life to me.</item>
        <item id="4">One of my old charges was a cheat and a scoundrel; and swindled me out of my pay. Some payback would be nice.</item>
        <item id="5">I failed in my duties; it ruined my reputation, and is a stain on my honor.</item>
        <item id="6">I served (or serve) with a team of bodyguards, that offer protection to various people traveling in dangerous areas.</item>
      </select>
      <select name="Flaw" type="List" optional="true">
        <item id="1">I am paranoid and overly protective, never letting those I guard out of my sight.</item>
        <item id="2">I’m lax in my duties; and this has gotten me into some trouble before.</item>
        <item id="3">Yes, actually; I do know best, and you will do as I say.</item>
        <item id="4">Sometimes my aggression towards strangers gets those I protect in more trouble, rather than help to avoid it.</item>
        <item id="5">I view myself and those I protect as higher than other people; looking down on the peasantry.</item>
        <item id="6">I am rigid in my hatred of criminals. I don’t care why you did it or how long ago it was; you’re still filth in my eyes.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Network" type="Background Feature" source="Silverware DnD" id="ID_SLV_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCOUT_NETWORK">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>I have a keen eye when it comes to reconnaisance. My companions and I can travel through woods easily; and I can always pick out the safest route to take through wilderness. This doesn’t account for unseen, hidden or dangers that are not yet reported. But I can easily avoid nests and areas where feral beasts might hang around.
      You can contact local scout establishment for information on local hazards, general information and tips on the area. You can additionaly give report on situations where scout initiative would help you by giving additional info on a specific subject or a person. You always have to report back on major events. Scout initiative can be subject to hierarchy and reputation by DM's discretion.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Network" />
  </element>
  <element name="Scout Initiative Spells" type="Background Feature" source="Silverware DnD" id="ID_SLV_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCOUT_INITIATIVE_SPELLS">
    <description>
      <p>
        <em>Prerequisite: Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature</em>
      </p>
      <p>For you, the spells on the Scout Initiative Spells table are added to the spell list of your spellcasting class. (If you are a multiclass character with multiple spell lists, these spells are added to all of them.)</p>
      <h5>SCOUT INITIATIVE SPELLS</h5>
      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <td>Spell Level</td>
            <td>Spells</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tr>
          <td>Cantrip</td>
          <td>
            <em>message, guidance</em>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>1st</td>
          <td>
            <em>wild cunning, comprehend languages, disguise self</em>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>2nd</td>
          <td>
            <em>animal messenger, suggestion, pass without trace</em>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>3rd</td>
          <td>
            <em>clairvoyance, gaseous form, sending</em>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>4th</td>
          <td>
            <em>arcane eye, dimension door, greater invisibility</em>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>5th</td>
          <td>
            <em>commune with nature, scrying, seeming </em>
          </td>
        </tr>
      </table>
      <p class="indent">If you use a spell focus, it probably has the form with an emblem of the scout initiative. Characters sees the emblem with a wisdom score of 12 or higher knows that you are a scout.</p>
      <p class="indent">Knack for information and curiosity sometimes leads you to a danger.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description> </description>
    </sheet>
    <spellcasting all="true" extend="true">
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDANCE</extend>
      <extend>ID_GGTR_SPELL_WILD_CUNNING</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_MESSENGER</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING</extend>
      <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING</extend>
    </spellcasting>
  </element>
</elements>